<table name="SYSPROC.ADMIN_TASK_ADD">
    <sql_name>SYSPROC.ADMIN_TASK_ADD</sql_name>
    <singular_name>SYSPROC.ADMIN_TASK_ADD</singular_name>
    <plural_name>SYSPROC.ADMIN_TASK_ADD</plural_name>
    <function>SYSPROC.ADMIN_TASK_ADD</function>
    <description/>
    <parameters>
        <parm name="NAME" ordinal="1" mode="IN">
            <title>Task name</title>
            <type>VARCHAR</type>
        </parm>
        <parm name="BEGIN_DATE" ordinal="2" mode="IN">
            <title>First run date</title>
            <type>TIMESTAMP</type>
        </parm>
        <parm name="BEGIN_TIME" ordinal="2" mode="IN">
            <title>First run time</title>
            <type>TIMESTAMP</type>
        </parm>
        <parm name="END_DATE" ordinal="3" mode="IN">
            <title>Last run date</title>
            <type>TIMESTAMP</type>
        </parm>
        <parm name="END_TIME" ordinal="3" mode="IN">
            <title>Last run time</title>
            <type>TIMESTAMP</type>
        </parm>
        <parm name="MAX_INVOCATIONS" ordinal="4" mode="IN">
            <title>Maximum runs allowed</title>
            <type>INTEGER</type>
        </parm>
        <parm name="SCHEDULE" ordinal="5" mode="IN">
            <title>Cron schedule</title>
            <type>VARCHAR</type>
        </parm>
        <parm name="PROCEDURE_SCHEMA" ordinal="6" mode="IN">
            <title>Procedure's schema</title>
            <type>VARCHAR</type>
        </parm>
        <parm name="PROCEDURE_NAME" ordinal="7" mode="IN">
            <title>Procedure's name</title>
            <type>VARCHAR</type>
        </parm>
        <parm name="PROCEDURE_INPUT" ordinal="8" mode="IN">
            <title>PROCEDURE_INPUT</title>
            <type>CLOB</type>
		    <info>
<![CDATA[
<pre><code>
Specifies the input parameters of the DB2 stored procedure this task will execute.

This parameter must contain an SQL statement that returns one row of data.

The returned values will be passed as parameters to the stored procedure

The number of columns returned by the SQL statement must match the total 
number (and type) of arguments for the procedure and must contain a single 
row. For output parameters, the value itself is ignored, but should be of 
the same SQL data type the stored procedure requires.

This SQL statement is executed every time the task is executed.  If the SQL 
statement fails, the task's status will be set to "NOTRUN" and specific SQLCODE 
information will be recorded.  If the statement does not return a result set,
does not return a row, returns multiple rows or result sets the task will not be
executed.  The task's status will be set to "NOTRUN" and SQLCODE SQL1465N will
be set to indicate that this parameter is invalid.  

If the statement result contains serialized XML parameters, the total size of
all XML parameters combined is limited to 256 kilobytes.  If the result exceeds
this threshold, the task's status will be set to "NOTRUN".  SQLCODE -302 and
SQLSTATE 22001 will be set to indicate that data truncation has occurred.

To view the task’s status, use the SYSTOOL.ADMIN_TASK_STATUS view.

If this parameter is set to NULL, no parameters are passed to the stored
procedure.

This is an input parameter of type CLOB(2M)
</code></pre>
]]>
		</info>
        </parm>
        <parm name="OPTIONS" ordinal="9" mode="IN" visible="false" disabled="true">
            <title>Option</title>
            <type>INT</type>
	        <value>NULL</value>
        </parm>
        <parm name="REMARKS" ordinal="10" mode="IN">
            <title>Comments</title>
            <type>VARCHAR</type>
        </parm>
    </parameters>
</table>
