<!--
  Copyright IBM Corp. 2007 All rights reserved.

  Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  You may obtain a copy of the License at

      http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  limitations under the License.
-->
<menu type="leaf" branchDirectory="">
  <description>Introduction</description>
  <pageWindow target="_final">
  	<title>Database Problem Determination</title>
    <panel name="main" PrimaryContainer="true">
    	<RAW><![CDATA[
<h1>Database Problem Determination</h1>
<table>
<tr><td style="max-width:400px;padding:5px;">
<p>The database problem determination workshop is designed around a series of scenarios demonstrating common problems that can occur within a database. These scenarios are designed to operate on a small system allowing a database administrator to experience and identify problems on a non-production system given them experience to work on production systems. </p>
<p>Each scenario recreates specific database problem using a specific workload to allow you to studying the effects of the problem on the system. The scenario will also highlight available monitoring within the database that can then be used to identify when this problem is occurring and identify who and what is causing the given problem. </p>
<p>While these scenarios do not cover how to solve the problem it is possible to use the scenario infrastructure to test possible solution or even use the underling infrastructure to recreate a problem and test a possible solution before implementing the solution on a given production system.</p>
<br/><br/><p>At the bottom of the scenario list is a tutorial that will allow you to capture workload on a given system and create a workload that can simulate the workload on a given system. </p>
</td></tr>
</table>
]]></RAW>
    </panel>
  </pageWindow>
</menu>
